aternos.org 2019-09-01

# Privacy Policy | Aternos

**Welcome to the privacy policy of Aternos,**  
We take the protection of your data very seriously and store only what we have to. In this policy, we will try to explain as good and comprehensible as possible which data we store and why. 

If you have any questions regarding your data, you can always write to us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

Legally responsible for the protection of your data is the Aternos UG: 

**Aternos UG (haftungsbeschränkt)**  
Heussallee 40  
53113 Bonn  
+49 228 18038354

Represented by: Matthias Neid ([[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)) 

## Which data do we store and why?

After we have clarified this we can now talk about your data that we store: When you sign up you have to enter your username, your email address and your password or you link a Google/Facebook account. If you link a Google/Facebook account, we save your account identifier and the email address of that account. 

Usually, your **username** cannot be traced back to you except if it contains your name or if you also use it on other platforms. Because of that, we protect your username the same way we protect personal data. 

We only use your **email address** to reset your password or to reactivate your account after it was closed. You receive an email with a link to perform that action in those cases, that have to be executed manually on our website. We will never use your email address for a newsletter or anything like that. If you sign up through your Google/Facebook account, we only save your email address in case you forgot which email address you have used to sign up. We will never send you an email in this case. 

Your **password** is already concealed on your computer (hash) and will then be stored with more security (hash + salt) on our servers. So your password will never reach our servers in plaintext and is extra secured. 

We also save the **point in time** of your registration to create statistics. Besides that, we have to save that time to be able to prove that you have accepted this policy. 

All **settings** of your Minecraft server and all **files** that are created by your Minecraft server are saved on our servers. Furthermore, we send this data as a backup to your Google Drive account if you want that and have it enabled. 

Furthermore, we store how many and which **players** are currently on your Minecraft server to display them on the website in your account and to determine statistics on the total number of players. 

We basically never save your **IP address** when you use our website. But it is possible, that your Minecraft server writes your IP address and the IP addresses of other players into a log file. This log file is overwritten on every start and can always be deleted by reinstalling the server. You can always see your log file at <https://aternos.org/log/>. 

To be able to understand what happened when errors or problems occur we save **miscellaneous activities** on our website in a log file, e. g. when you start your server, who enters or leaves your server, when you up- or download a world or when you change your email address or password. This data will not be processed automatically, it will only be used manually to solve errors or to help you. 

## Who has access to your data and why?

To operate our website, we need the services of various third parties that may have contact with your data. We have an agreement with all of the companies listed below to ensure that they only use your information for their intended purpose. 

**Google Inc. or Google Ireland Limited** : We use Google Analytics on our website for detailed statistics. Your activities are pseudonymized, recorded and stored by Google. Your IP address will be anonymized. 

**Cloudflare Inc** : CDN and WAF (performance and security enhancements) for our website. All data sent to our website will be reviewed and forwarded by Cloudflare. 

**Message Systems Inc** : We use the SparkPost service to send emails on the above occasions. 

**Snigel Web Services Ltd** : Snigel Web provides ads on our website. Consent to third-party data processing for advertising purposes is requested separately from this policy when you visit our website. 

**oneCorp Systems, owned by Tristan Fischer** : oneCorp provides us with the necessary hardware to operate our website and the game servers and may only in exceptional cases have access to the drives on which your data is stored. 

## Your rights

We save all mentioned data starting from the registration until you decide to close your account here: <https://aternos.org/close/> In doing so, we will delete your data 7 days after the closing to avoid possible issues or to cancel an unintended closing. Apart from this, you have the right to complete deletion of your data, but we ask you to use the functions mentioned above. 

You have the right to information about your personal data as well as for correction. Additionally, you can limit the processing or contradict it completely. Please contact us with sufficient verification at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

Furthermore, according to §77 GDPR, you have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority if you believe that the processing of your personal data is illicit. 

The provision of your personal data is neither legally nor contractually binding and is optional. If you do not agree to this policy, we cannot offer you our services, unfortunately. 

You are only allowed to agree to this policy if you are at least 16 years old (or less if your country has different regulations) or if consent is given by the holder of your parental responsibility.
